<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Andrew Vida]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewvida.heroku.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewvida.heroku.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-27T23:16:52-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewvida.heroku.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Vida]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watir Bazaar Recap]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewvida.heroku.com/blog/2012/03/27/watir-bazaar-recap/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-27T22:42:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewvida.heroku.com/blog/2012/03/27/watir-bazaar-recap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.twitter.com/bramhaghosh">Bramha Ghosh</a> and I were honored to speak at the Test Automation Bazaar, otherwise known as &#8220;Watir Bazaar&#8221;, on March 24-25.</p>

<p>We presented our journey in implementing Specification by Example in a mid-size enterprise environment at Grange Insurance
in Columbus, OH.  We covered things such as what our environment was like previously, how we were able to convince management
to try Acceptance Test Driven Development, how our team reacted, things that worked and how we plan to move forward.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>It was amazing to be surrounded by so many passionate developers and testers! Even though Watir is used at many places such
as Facebook, GAP, and Expedia, it&#8217;s still got a small home grown feel.  The conference was small but everyone there had a voice
into how Watir would progress into the future.  After all, it is an open source project!</p>

<p>All of the conference sessions were recorded and you may find them <a href="http://kondoot.com/watir">here</a>.</p>

<p>Our session can be found <a href="http://kondoot.com/videos/b14db732bb3">here</a>.</p>

<script src="http://speakerdeck.com/embed/4f63779f72b23d001f01f071.js"></script>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[new-post]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewvida.heroku.com/blog/2012/03/27/new-post/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-27T22:29:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewvida.heroku.com/blog/2012/03/27/new-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moving from Wordpress]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewvida.heroku.com/blog/2012/01/08/moving-from-wordpress/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-08T12:03:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewvida.heroku.com/blog/2012/01/08/moving-from-wordpress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, I&#8217;ve done it!  I&#8217;ve taken the plunge to move my blog from Wordpress.  As any good software developer
will tell you, it&#8217;s more fun to create stuff than to use something out of the box, so after looking around at
my options, I decided to use Octopress.</p>

<!-- More -->


<h3>What is Octopress</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.octopress.org">Octopress</a> is basically Jekyll on steroids.  To get started with Jekyll, you have to write your own HTML
templates, CSS, Javascript and set up your configuration.  I was okay with most of that, but I suck at
design.  I love clean crisp design, but for some reason, I&#8217;m missing that designer skill.  So, since Octopress
does that for me, I was in love!</p>

<p>Other cool things about Octopress is that it uses HTML5.  It also has built in 3rd party support for Twitter,
Github, Google Plus, Disqus, Pinboard and Delicious to name a few. It also has a ton of plugins.  Some come
from the Jekyll community, but others are specifically made for Octopress.  Oh, and did I mention it&#8217;s open
source?!</p>

<h2>Getting Started</h2>

<p>Getting a new blog set up is a piece of cake.  All you have to do is fork or clone the Github <a href="https://github.com/imathis/octopress">repo</a>.
Next, you have to set up your deployment.  They make it easy to deploy using Github pages or to Heroku.  I
decided on deploying to heroku.  I like the fact that I can keep my source on Github and then push directly to Heroku.
Octopress&#8217;s documentation makes this so easy for you.</p>

<h2>Add Some Content</h2>

<p>Adding a new post is as simple as running a rake task.  It creates a simple markdown file for you that you can edit
in any editor you wish.  I use VIM since I&#8217;m pretty familiar with it.  Those that use VIM daily will tell you that
it&#8217;s difficult to go back to anything else.  Now you&#8217;ve got all of that VIM hotness available to you to while blogging.
It definitely beats that Wordpress template thingy that is hard to use.</p>

<p>As I&#8217;m writing, I take a peek at what my post looks like online.  I set up <a href="http://pow.cx">POW</a> to host my blog locally.
I run a rake task that watches my source and as I save my buffer in VIM, I can instantly see what my post looks like in
the browser.  I&#8217;ve never used POW before, but will use it for everything going forward, especially as I have many projects
set up on my machine and sometimes want to run multiple Rack applications.</p>

<h2>What&#8217;s Next</h2>

<p>I&#8217;ve already learned so much by moving my blog to Octopress.  I get to host my source up on Github, deploy to Heroku,
use VIM for everything, set up POW for my Rack server, and hack on an open source Ruby project.  Next, on my list of
things to do is to make my blog look a little nicer and change from the default template.  I&#8217;m hoping since blogging
is now a little bit of coding, I&#8217;ll do it more.  Look forward to many more posts from me in the future - and if not,
be sure to call me out on it!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[testing]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewvida.heroku.com/blog/2012/01/07/testing/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-07T23:14:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewvida.heroku.com/blog/2012/01/07/testing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now that we know who you are, I know who I am. I&#8217;m not a mistake! It all makes sense! In a comic, you know how you can tell who the arch-villain&#8217;s going to be? He&#8217;s the exact opposite of the hero. And most times they&#8217;re friends, like you and me! I should&#8217;ve known way back when&#8230; You know why, David? Because of the kids. They called me Mr Glass.</p>

<p>Now that there is the Tec-9, a crappy spray gun from South Miami. This gun is advertised as the most popular gun in American crime. Do you believe that shit? It actually says that in the little book that comes with it: the most popular gun in American crime. Like they&#8217;re actually proud of that shit.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>Now that we know who you are, I know who I am. I&#8217;m not a mistake! It all makes sense! In a comic, you know how you can tell who the arch-villain&#8217;s going to be? He&#8217;s the exact opposite of the hero. And most times they&#8217;re friends, like you and me! I should&#8217;ve known way back when&#8230; You know why, David? Because of the kids. They called me Mr Glass.</p>

<p>You think water moves fast? You should see ice. It moves like it has a mind. Like it knows it killed the world once and got a taste for murder. After the avalanche, it took us a week to climb out. Now, I don&#8217;t know exactly when we turned on each other, but I know that seven of us survived the slide&#8230; and only five made it out. Now we took an oath, that I&#8217;m breaking now. We said we&#8217;d say it was the snow that killed the other two, but it wasn&#8217;t. Nature is lethal but it doesn&#8217;t hold a candle to man.</p>

<p>&#8220;http://slipsum.com&#8221;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Acceptance Tests To Define Done]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewvida.heroku.com/blog/2012/01/06/using-acceptance-tests-to-define-done/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-06T14:50:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewvida.heroku.com/blog/2012/01/06/using-acceptance-tests-to-define-done</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(This post was originally posted on <a href="https://twitter.com/ajimholmes">Jim Holmes&#8217;</a> <a href="http://frazzleddad.blogspot.com/2011/12/31-days-of-testing-kickoff.html">&#8220;31 Days of Testing&#8221;</a> blog series,
but I thought it served some value here as well.)</p>

<p>Have you ever been on a team and was asked “What is the definition of done?” You respond by saying,
“When all of your automated tests pass, and there are no bugs, then you have satisfied the acceptance
criteria. Done!” Which then is responded to by “Well, how do I define the acceptance criteria?” Good question!</p>

<!-- More -->


<h3>Understanding the Feature</h3>

<p>First things first – you have to understand what feature you’ll be building. Building the right product
and building the product right takes communication and collaboration between your product owner and your team.</p>

<p>The reason for all of the collaboration is that we’re trying to build a shared understanding of what needs
to be done and also produce examples that are easy to maintain. There are many ways to work collaboratively
and ultimately, you have to decide what works best for your team.</p>

<p>The team I’m currently on has found that smaller workshops work best for us. Those workshops, otherwise
known as “Three Amigos”, include a business analyst, a developer and a tester who share a similar understanding of the domain.</p>

<p>Lets hypothetically say you’re discussing a shopping cart feature for your site. Start by defining the goals
of this feature. By starting with the goal, you’ll let everyone know why they’re spending their time
on implementing the feature. If you can’t come up with a good reason why, then maybe the product owner is wasting everyone’s time.</p>

<p>We’ve used the Feature Injection template from Chris Matts and Liz Keogh to help us successfully describe why: <br/>
<strong>As a</strong> &lt;type of stakeholder&gt;<br/>
<strong>I want</strong> &lt;a feature&gt;<br/>
<strong>So that</strong> &lt;I can meet some goal&gt;<br/></p>

<p>Here’s our feature description:<br/>
As an online shopper<br/>
I want to add items to my shopping cart<br/>
So that I can purchase them<br/></p>

<h3>Determining Acceptance Criteria</h3>

<p>Next, your team needs to determine what the system needs to do to meet those goals-the Acceptance Criteria.</p>

<p>In your Three Amigos meeting, be sure to ask questions to clear up assumptions, such as “Are there any
products that cannot be purchased online?” or “Does the shopper need to be authenticated to purchase?”.</p>

<p>Remember, the scope of feature should be high level as we only want to identify what the application needs
to do and not how it’s implemented. Leave that part to the people that know how to design software. It was
determined by the team that the following are in scope:</p>

<ul>
<li>Only authenticated shoppers can add items to the shopping cart.</li>
<li>Cannot add refrigerators to shopping cart.</li>
<li>Only 25 items can be added.</li>
<li>Shopper can remove items from shopping cart.</li>
<li>Shopper can change quantity of items after adding it to the cart.</li>
</ul>


<p>Hey, now we have some acceptance criteria!</p>

<h3>Acceptance Criteria lead to Acceptance Tests</h3>

<p>We’ve used communication and collaboration to determine why a feature is necessary and what the system needs
to do to at a high level, so now we can come up with some examples to test our acceptance criteria.</p>

<p>To do this, we’ll write some Cucumber scenarios. We’ve chosen Cucumber for all of the reasons mentioned
in <a href="http://frazzleddad.blogspot.com/2011/12/31-days-of-testingday-15-cucumber-is.html">Tim Wingfield’s post on Day 15</a>.
If you haven’t read it, go back and check it out. It’s an excellent post on the benefits of employing Cucumber.</p>

<p>Here are a few scenarios that were created:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='text'><span class='line'>Given the shopper is a guest
</span><span class='line'>When they try to add an item to their shopping cart
</span><span class='line'>Then they will receive the error &quot;Only authenticated shoppers can add items to their shopping cart.&quot;
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>




<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='text'><span class='line'>Given an authenticated shopper
</span><span class='line'>When they click the &quot;Add Item to Cart&quot; button
</span><span class='line'>Then they will have an item in their shopping cart
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>




<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='text'><span class='line'>Given an authenticated shopper with an item in their shopping cart
</span><span class='line'>When they click the &quot;Remove Item&quot; button
</span><span class='line'>Then that item is no longer in their shopping cart
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>These are only a few of the examples that were developed as part of the Three Amigos meeting.
On our team, the output of the Three Amigos is a Cucumber feature file. We now have a shared understanding
and a definition of done! We can pass on our failing acceptance tests to the Dev team to begin their work. They
will begin by creating failing unit tests and writing enough code to make them pass. Once they are passing, they
can then run the acceptance tests. Once those are passing then the feature is complete. We’re done! Those acceptance
tests will be added to the regression suite to be ran anytime to ensure that the feature remains done. Now the feature
can be demonstrated to the product owner at the next review.</p>

<p>What we’ve just done is taken a trip around the Acceptance Test Driven Development cycle. Just remember,
it’s not about the tools or the technology, but rather the communication and collaboration. Our ultimate goal
is to deliver high quality software that functions as the product owner intended. By including QA in the entire process,
we can eliminate many of the problems that plague us earlier so that they don’t make it to production. Quality
is not just a QA function, it’s a team function.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
